





Last Active: 18-Jun-20 Last Modified: 3-Jun-20

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Experienced and knowledgeable Information Technology professional looking for position of as a DevOps engineer. Having 7 years of experience from server troubleshooting, linux administration to scripting, orchestration of servers using salt, building Idap containers using docker, setting up email servers, firewalls, Internet access control, monitoring and alerting systems, has helped to develop a strong appreciation and knowledge of DevOps.

Work Experience

- CenturyLink Technologies India Pvt. Ltd. as Senior Software Engineer Apr 2019 to Till Date
 - * Setting up and maintaining Kubernetes clusters for various environments.
 - * Written custom docker images to deploy dotnet applications on Linux Machines.
 - * Automated versioning of docker images based on commit message using shell scripting.
 - * Automated Blue/Green and canary deployment model on Kubernetes.
 - * Setting up and maintaining Confluent Kafka clusters along with kafka rest, kafka connect, kafka ksql, schema registry.
 - * Created a security model both authentication/authorization for confluent cluster.
 - Written a spring boot application to automate creation of users and acls in confluent-kafka.
 - * Worked on setting up various components of Kubernetes such as Deployments, Pods, Services, NodePort, Ingress, HPA, metric servers, Kubernetes dashboard.
 - Created and maintained pipelines in gitlab ci, good and Jenkins for various spring boot, python applications
- GlobalLogic as Associate Consultant

Feb 2018 to Apr 2019

- * Monitoring and troubleshooting on-premise environment which comprises of over 1500 servers using Nagios and check mk.
- Was involved in migrating the on-premise environment to GCP.
- * Have worked GCP virtual machines, IAM, Data Storage, Resource Management, Monitoring, Interconnecting networks, GKE.
- * Monitoring and troubleshooting of Hadoop ecosystem components using ambari.
- * Writing automation scripts on GCP using google api client and python.
- * Infrastructure automation using Terraform along with AWS.
- * Designing build and deploy jobs for various apps using Jenkins and shell scripting.
- * Have lessened the time taken by deploy jobs significantly by using parallelization in shell.
- Yukthi Systems as Devops, Member of Technical Staff Jan 2015 to Feb 2018

Setting up firewalls using iptables and squid, email servers with postfix dovecot openIdap and postgresql, making use

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

of scripting with postfix based on the requirements collected from clients.

Giving demos to client on the product, collecting the shortcomings, market for the product.

Automation of installation of OS(DEBIAN) using preseeding.

Automation of installation various modules email server using salt state files.

Using salt for configuration management on all the available nodes.

Shell scripting and mailfromd to process the email based on the requirement before sending it out.

Setting up of monitoring and alerting systems using prometheus and grafana, using python scripting to write exporters required for collecting the required metrics both software specific and hardware specific.

Using python with salt to automate repetitive tasks.

Played a major role in the team which implemented meta Idap using docker.

Indexing of attributes in Idap, migration of Idap from hdb to mdb, addition and modification of acl?s on Idap databases.

Writing spamassassin rules to control spam, feeding spam and ham to bayesian classifier.

Setting up webmail modules such SOGo, horde, roundcube, squirrelmail, making minor changes in the code if possible to meet client requirements.

Made use of postfix content filters, Idap to build server level user based HTML signature.

Installing SSL certificates using lets encrypt, certbot for apache, postfix and dovecot.

Fine tuning of parameters related to email server, web server.

Fixing the vulnerabilities in SSL by disabling weak ciphers, lower versions of SSL.

Writing systemd unit files and init scripts.

Performing stress tests on servers to estimate the maximum accommodation and preparing the document of the same.

Kernel upgradations, upgradation of OS [DEBIAN].

Setting up of file servers using samba, vpn servers using openvpn.

Setting up Urbackup.

Setting up MySQL master slave replication.

Preparing client related documents which explain the working of various above implemented modules. DNS management A, MX, CNAVE, SPF, TXT, NS records.

Linode management

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electronics/Telecommunication) from GPulla Reddy Engineering College, Kurnool in 2013

PG: no pg btech (ece) in 0

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Linux Administration			
Bash shell scripting			
Postfix, Dovecot, Fetchmail, Offllineimap			
IPTables, Squid			
Spamassassin, clamav			
Apache, Roundcube,			
Squirrelmail, Horde, SOGo, Kolab			
OPENLDAP			
DOCKER			
Salt, Knowledge of jenkins			
Cloud services.			
GIT			
Prometheus, Grafana			
ELK Stack			
Python			
MYSQL, POSTGRESQL			
HTML, CSS			
ProLiant Density Line and Blades Line			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Telugu	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
hindi	Beginner	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.